In this next cell, this is just the same function
下个单元格中的函数
that was in the solution for the FunkSVD function.
与在 FunkSVD 函数的解中创建的函数一样
You can see that it's leaning here with
可以看到模型正在学习
each iteration we're getting a smaller and smaller mean squared error.
每次迭代之后 均方误差都越来越小
We're going to go through 250 iterations and so this is going to take some time to do.
我们将迭代 250 次 需要运行一段时间
We have 15 latent features that we're using to try to understand the movies.
为了理解电影 我们使用了 15 个潜在特征
This is kind of arbitrary and choosing that is largely
这个值比较随意
based on trial and error a lot of times, so we'll let this run.
主要通过试错法确定这个数值
So that took some time but now you should have
让代码继续运行下去 运行时间较长
a user matrix and a movie matrix where you can use
现在你已经有一个用户矩阵和电影矩阵
the dot product of a row from the user matrix with a column of
可以使用用户矩阵的行与电影矩阵的列
the movie matrix and get any user movie prediction that you want.
之间的点积得出任何用户-电影预测值
So, the next thing that we're going to do is essentially allow for that to be the case.
接下来我们就这么预测
So we'll pass in the user matrix and
我们将传入用户矩阵和电影矩阵
the movie matrix along with a user ID and a movie ID,
以及用户 ID 和电影 ID
and what we want to get back is the predicted rating that
我们将根据这两个矩阵
that user would give to that movie based on these two matrices.
预测用户对该电影的评分
So, the first thing that we need to do is be able to index into
首先 我们需要找到用户和电影矩阵中的索引
the user and movie matrices to grab the particular user ID or movie ID.
并获得特定的用户 ID 或电影 ID
If you remember from some of the things that we did earlier,
如果你还记得之前的步骤的话
I'm just going to put this here.
我将代码放在这里
But essentially what we want to do is we can use an
我们可以使用 np.where 语句
np.where statement and we can look at where the user ID,
我们可以看看这个用户 ID 所在的位置
something is equal to that user ID, right?
看看传入的值是否等于该 user_id
So, we want this thing,
即 == user_id
and if it's equal to the user ID then we're going to pull that value out.
如果等于该 user_id 我们将提取该值
If you remember when we used the np.where before,
之前使用 np.where 语句的时候
it gives us back this nested thing where
它返回了这个嵌套结果
we're going to want to go into it and grab a particular number.
我们将从中获取特定的数字
So, in order to figure out what that series looks like,
为了查看这串索引是什么
I want to look at the training data frame.
我们来看看训练 dataframe
If we look at this, this is essentially
这是我们要根据它
the user movie matrix that we were making those prediction lawn, right?
做出预测的电影矩阵
So this is the one that we were looking at.
即我们要查看的矩阵
You can see it's full of a bunch of null values
其中有很多零值
but an array of just this user ID and an array of
这是用户 ID 数组
this movie ID will give us the ability to index in and
这是电影 ID 数组
find the row column we should be pulling from the user movie matrices.
我们将通过它们得出从用户电影矩阵中提取值的行和列索引
So with that, here was what I did.
下面说说我的提取方式
I said basically, if you take the index of this thing,
如果对它调用 index
that gives you back the users,
返回的是用户
and if you take the columns,
如果调用 columns
this gives you back the movies, right?
返回的是电影
So these are the movies and those are the columns,
这些是电影 这些是列
and then all I did was I turned those into np arrays.
我只是将它们变成了 NumPy 数组
So, I created these two things that were NumPy arrays and I just called it
我创建了这两个 NumPy 数组
user ID series and movie ID series and I just did a mess, NumPy arrays.
称之为 user_ids_series 和 movie_ids_series 并设为 NumPy 数组
So I said, give me an array of this index,
获取这个索引数组
and movie IDs series.
然后是 movie_ids_series
Okay. So now I have these movie and user indices that I can use
Ok现在获得了这些可以使用的电影索引和用户索引
and basically I want to index into that thing and find the particular movie or user ID.
我希望通过索引找到特定的电影或用户 ID
So if I go in and I say,
也就是说
hey, where this thing is equal to this,
如果这个值等于这个值
pull that index because that's the row that I'm going to want from the u matrix, right?
则提取该索引 因为它是我要从 U 矩阵中获取的行
So this is like, the user row that I want is equal to this,
所以我想要的用户行等于这个
and the movie column that I want is equal to,
并且我想要的电影列等于这个
basically the same thing but from
两个基本一样
the movie IDs series and where that's equal to the movie ID.
但是来自 movie_ids_series 并且等于 movie_id
Again we're going to just index into this thing because if you remember from before,
然后传入索引 就像之前那样
it gives you this sort of nested thing.
它会返回嵌套结果
Then basically, our prediction is just that we are going to take
预测等于这两项的点积
the dot product of the user matrix where the row is equal to what I call the user row,
对于用户矩阵来说 行等于这个 user_row
and the column, we just want all of the columns for that user.
列是用户对应的所有列
Then, we want to take the dot product of that with
即这部分与
the movie matrix that they're passing in and then,
传入的电影矩阵的点积
here we want sort of the opposite we want,
电影矩阵正好相反
the movie column and all the rows.
我们想要所有行和 movie_col
If we do that, then that should give us the prediction and you can see,
这样就获得了预测值
so like for this particular user movie pair,
对于这个用户-电影对
so for user eight on movie 2844,
即用户 8 对电影 2844 的评分
our prediction would be 6.65.
预测结果是 6.65